<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT Architecture Cheat Sheet – Application View</title>
    <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Application View on IT Architecture Cheat Sheet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: Web Application</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/web-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/web-application/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web applications are accessed through a browser to directly use the application on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Installation Required: Unlike traditional standalone applications that require installation, web applications can be accessed simply by connecting to a website through a browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version Synchronization: When connecting to a web application, the latest version is always used, avoiding issues caused by version inconsistencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-Platform Usage: Web applications can be accessed using standard browsers, eliminating compatibility issues across different types and versions of computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low Client-Side Load: Most of the computation is performed on the server-side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security: Connecting to web applications over public networks introduces more cybersecurity risks, such as XSS, SQL injection, CSRF attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity: Web applications are divided into frontend components responsible for display and backend components handling business logic, making the overall process more abstract and complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser Version Issues: Different users may have different browser versions installed, requiring consideration for browser compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Offline Usage: Web applications cannot be used when there is no internet connection. Modern Progressive Web Applications (PWAs) address this issue by caching data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Speed Issues: Some clients may have unstable internet speeds, which can affect performance. Techniques such as caching and reducing/delaying network requests need to be considered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limitations on Software and Hardware Access: Due to browser support and security concerns, web applications cannot access all hardware information and user files in the same way as native applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: Progressive Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/progressive-web-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/progressive-web-apps/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PWA (Progressive Web Application) is a special form of web application that provides some functionalities of native applications. It achieves this by defining information such as icons, theme colors, and utilizing service workers to provide partial functionality and push notifications even when the network is unavailable. PWAs aim to offer native-like features across different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing cross-platform applications in a native-like format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not requiring constant internet connectivity for the web application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offering better services to users in limited network environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the advantages of web applications, such as cross-platform compatibility, no installation or updates, PWAs have the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App-like Experience: They can generate desktop shortcuts and icons, similar to traditional applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offline Usage: They can provide core functionality even when the network is unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast Loading: Due to data caching in the browser, PWAs have faster startup times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the general disadvantages of web applications, PWAs have the following drawbacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex Caching Mechanism: Managing offline and online data caching with different update strategies can be challenging and complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inconsistent Browser Support: Support for PWAs may vary across different browsers and devices, with some browsers lacking complete compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: Mobile App</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile application is a specialized software application designed to be installed on a mobile device, usually downloaded from an application store. Different operating systems have different default development frameworks, requiring separate development approaches or the use of cross-platform frameworks such as React Native or Flutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenience and ease of use: Mobile applications can be directly installed from an application store without the need for additional downloads or entering URLs. Additionally, the interfaces are often optimized for mobile usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High supportability: Once granted user permissions, mobile applications can fully utilize various hardware features and access system information on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offline usability: Most mobile applications can function offline unless network features are required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High development costs: Separate development is needed for iOS and Android, and multiple versions of devices from different manufacturers need to be tested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatibility issues with older devices: Consideration must be given to the limited software and hardware support on older models of mobile devices, as some users may still be using them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: No Code App</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/no-code-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/application-architecture/application-view/no-code-app/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Code App is a SaaS service that allows users to develop customized applications without the need for programming. It provides a UI design tool where users can drag and drop interface elements and define the actions to be performed when buttons are pressed. By abstracting the logic design process, Codeless uses visual tools to design user interfaces and action logics. The platform then executes the program logic based on the selected rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Code App is suitable for developing simple program functionalities such as form filling, data presentation, or basic interactive features. It may not be suitable for complex UI interfaces and processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No programming required: Users can design their desired software interfaces and functionalities without the need for coding, making it accessible for non-programmers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functionality limitations: The capabilities of Codeless are constrained by the framework designed within the Codeless App platform. It may not support the development of more complex applications and processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
