<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT Architecture Cheat Sheet – Storage Infra</title>
    <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage Infra on IT Architecture Cheat Sheet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: DAS</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/das/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/das/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct Attached Storage (DAS) connects disk drives to the computer or server directly through hardware. It can use connections such as SATA, SAS, USB, etc., to connect the hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal computers or small workstations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple architecture: Just mount the hard drive and it&amp;rsquo;s ready to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost-effective: Compared to NAS and SAN, no additional configuration or server is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most DAS devices cannot share disk access with other servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: NAS</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/nas/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Network Attached Storage (NAS) is a standalone file access server that connects hard drives to the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared disk storage for enterprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple servers accessing the same disk space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple servers can access the data simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports mounting multiple hard drives, providing larger storage capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With mechanisms like RAID, it can reduce the risk of data loss due to a single drive failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher cost: Compared to DAS, NAS requires a separate server and multiple hard drives, resulting in higher costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex architecture and management: NAS requires management of servers, networking, and storage configurations, making it more challenging to manage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single point of failure: If the NAS server experiences a network or power interruption, it will be unable to provide data access services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: SAN</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/san/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/san/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Storage Area Network (SAN) utilizes a dedicated fiber network, multiple disk arrays, and multiple switches to form a storage space. Although it consists of multiple disk arrays, it can be mounted and used by servers just like regular hard drives. SAN addresses the risk of single point of failure found in NAS and provides faster access speed, but it comes with a significantly higher price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared disk storage and server usage in large enterprises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates single point of failure: Multiple disk arrays are available for access, preventing connectivity issues caused by a single disk array failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast access: SAN utilizes fiber optics to access data, resulting in faster access speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does not consume LAN traffic: SAN uses a dedicated network for data access, ensuring other LAN services are unaffected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy scalability: With multiple disk arrays, storage capacity can be increased in batches without impacting service operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly higher cost: SAN requires multiple disk arrays and fiber network infrastructure, resulting in higher expenses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex management: SAN requires additional management of disk array devices and maintenance of fiber network configurations, making it complex to manage with a steep learning curve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: RAID</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/raid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/raid/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAID (Redundant Array of Independent Disks) is a technology that utilizes multiple disks to redundantly store data, reducing the risk of data loss due to a single disk failure. There are various levels of RAID, such as RAID 0, RAID 1, RAID 6, each with different redundancy logic and backup methods. RAID can be implemented through hardware or software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data storage with important data where the goal is to avoid data loss caused by a single disk failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundant protection: Reduces the risk of data loss by storing data across multiple disks with redundancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High read/write efficiency: With multiple disks, simultaneous reading and writing to different disks can improve overall performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher cost: Different RAID levels may require additional redundant disks, and specialized RAID disk arrays may need to be purchased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex management: RAID requires consideration of different RAID levels and storage configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential decrease in write speed: In certain RAID modes, simultaneous writing to multiple disks may result in decreased write speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to address localized risks: RAID alone cannot protect against localized risks such as power outages or natural disasters that may cause data loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: Block Storage</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/block-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/block-storage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block Storage is a method of storing a large amount of data by distributing it across multiple servers in individual blocks of data. It allows for both sequential and random file access and can store structured and related sets of files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared folders within an enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data folders mounted by virtual machines (VMs) or containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage of large amounts of files: Block Storage can handle high-capacity storage requirements through horizontal scaling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage of structured files: Block Storage supports storage of structured data, such as relational databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex architecture and management: Block Storage requires more configuration and management, including block allocation and access control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High setup cost: Establishing and maintaining Block Storage typically involves significant costs, including hardware equipment, storage software, and data protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet: Object Storage</title>
      <link>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/object-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradhuang9999.github.io/IT-Architecture-CheatSheet/cheat-sheet/data-architecture/storage-infra/object-storage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Object Storage is a storage architecture that treats each file as an individual object with a unique ID. Access to these files is done through the use of RESTful API. Files can include various types such as images, videos, or general documents, and they can be flexibly stored in a distributed environment. Object Storage is often accompanied by redundant multiple backups to prevent data loss in case of disasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Cases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large-scale file storage needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Delivery Networks (CDNs), photo albums, video streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent files: Storing a large number of images, videos, and general documents, rather than a group of related structured files (e.g., databases).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy storage and backup: Each file is stored independently, allowing for distributed storage and backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy access: Files can be accessed through a RESTful API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unable to store structured data: Object Storage is primarily used for storing unstructured files and is not suitable for structured data or relational data storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cannot be mounted as a network drive for traditional operating systems: Object Storage cannot be directly mounted as a network drive for traditional operating systems like Block Storage. Instead, access is done through an API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex architecture: Object Storage has a relatively complex architecture, requiring more configuration and management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
